what's up everybody this is Nick at
bobbed.com and today we are talking
about the best post workout supplements
a lot of people can't live without their
pre-workouts but your post-workout
nutrition is also pretty important your
overall calories and macronutrients and
sleep and workouts and everything those
are also probably more important
nonetheless there are a wide range of
supplements that one can consume after a
workout for an array of effects so we've
got everything here from Mass scanners
if that's your goal we've also got
antioxidant supplements we've got
carbohydrate supplements creatine and a
lot more so stick around we're going to
cover every single angle of the
post-workout nutrition puzzle
[Music]
before I go on I didn't need to make it
clear this is not medical advice I'm not
a medical professional that's like an
important disclaimer to get out there if
you're going to make any changes to your
supplement regimen your nutrition
regimen or your workout regimen or just
any changes to your health uh be sure to
talk to a doctor who knows your
individual history and medications and
everything else like that so I'm going
to give a quick overview of the whole
General category of post-workout
nutrition but uh just because this is
probably way clicking this video I'm
going to show you right now a number one
pick overall for post-workout nutrition
so this guy here is Formula 12 from huge
supplements we like this one because it
has a lot of interesting ingredients
many of which people take pre-workout
but can actually be taken any time of
day to enhance your performance in the
gym so we're talking about ingredients
like beta alanine and beta in top of
that we've got some other nutrients here
and some carbohydrates as well that
might help too helpfully Spike insulin
I'm gonna give that into a minute but
for now
what is post-workout nutrition the world
of post-workout nutrition has changed
considerably in the last couple of
decades it used to be if you check out
any Muscle Max in the 90s they would
tell you that after you finish a workout
you should run not walk to a protein
shake and drink as quickly as possible
to maximize the benefits of the
post-workout anabolic window they've
since learned that really it's the
calories and macronutrients overall
throughout the day that are more
important than the timing nonetheless
exercise does produce a array of effects
on the body that could potentially
require or potentially be a little bit
better with certain nutrients in certain
supplements now really here today we've
got a whole array of reception
supplements so protein naturally is one
that a lot of people like to have after
a workout because it does indeed help to
feed your muscles and help them to
repair themselves we've also got
supplements here to help with your sleep
there's the area of creatine we've also
got different carbohydrate supplements
we've got some supplements here they're
going to help you to feed your glycogen
stores and going to help you to reach
your calorie goals as well we've also
got Mass gainers also got intra workout
supplements which I'm going to talk
about in a little bit but for now let's
get back to our top pick so formula 12
is an intra and a post-workout
supplement so it took home our awards
for the best post workout supplement and
the best intra workout supplement intra
workout of course just meaning during a
workout you've almost certainly had a
pre-workout supplements but there are
plenty of people who like to take a nice
big shaker bottle full of water with
some intro workout in it to help them
continue their workout while at the gym
that can be especially useful if you're
working out on an empty stomach but
nonetheless when you are exercising uh
it can be helpful to a lot of folks that
have a sort of carbohydrate supplement
to maintain your glycogen stores
throughout the workout keep it going for
a little bit longer help you to exert a
bit more power and there are other
ingredients in here as well that can be
very useful both intra and post workout
so the main thing I wanted to emphasize
there is that there are some fast
digesting insulin smacking carbohydrates
in here and that can be very useful
during a workout but also after a
workout because you get a nice Spike of
insulin and insulin is in fact like and
it's really good at sending nutrients to
your muscles a bit more quickly so the
main one here is mud carb which is an
interesting artificial blend of
carbohydrates but it's also
clustodextrin too which is very popular
in carbohydrate supplements we're going
to get into real dedicated carbohydrate
supplements later on this isn't crazy
high in carbohydrates it's got like
maybe about 15-20 grams of them in a
scoop there are other things in here as
well that can be useful for recovery so
there's plenty of antioxidants in here
and then we've got some alpha lipoic
acid and grape seed extract both of
which are very dense in antioxidants and
those can be very helpful for helping to
improve recovery potentially reducing
muscle soreness potentially reducing
inflammation as well so there's less up
here for recovery and also for
performance and also they come in a
range of really delicious flavors this
one here is candy apple I encourage you
to try it out and this one here
definitely takes home our award for best
post and intra workout supplement
overall let's get a bit more specific so
next we're getting to the most popular
perhaps area of post-workout nutrition
which is the protein shake right here we
have Wolverines whey protein isolate
which is our favorite way I flip on the
market as I mentioned we used to sort of
think you need to get away Shake
immediately after a workout the anabolic
window after workout isn't as important
as we used to think but nonetheless I
and a lot of folks like to have protein
pretty close after workout just because
you've typically burnt through a lot of
your stores and you also are typically
quite hungry and it's also a good idea
to get some extra amino acids into the
system to help your muscles repair
themselves right so this has a 26 grams
of protein you just have half a gram of
fat and one gram of carbohydrate this is
the honey cinnamon peanut butter flavor
it's absolutely delicious I've also got
the standard chocolate and vanilla
flavors as well on top of that in
addition to being like just so high in
protein with so much protein per calorie
it's basically like a chicken breast in
a cup but it tastes better you've also
got some ingested enzymes in here which
really elevates it above other
competitors in the market they're just
enzymes here is pet pain and protease
these help to digest proteins a bit more
easily and there has indeed been some
research suggesting that when you're
adding enzymes to a protein shake you
find amino acids in the bloodstream will
quickly than you do if you didn't have
the 10 science with it in other words
throwing in some enzymes can help to
break down more quickly and more
effectively and absorb and get to your
muscles where they're needed a little
bit faster before I go and I should
mention I know I'm kind of throwing a
lot of information here at you if you
want to go through this information in a
written form to go through it at your
own pace get a close look at the
ingredients and the research that I'm
citing you can because we wrote a
written version of this article so if
you just go to Google and write in bar
Ben best post workout supplements it'll
come right up you can check it out there
for now let's talk about the best post
workout for Muscle Recovery which kind
of combines elements from the first two
picks on this list we're talking about
caves re-caged so this has plenty of
protein as well as extra ingredients to
help to improve performance and Recovery
in the gym so one scoop of this is going
to be 140 calories and you're getting a
nice 28 grams of protein from whey
protein isolate it's also remarkably low
in carbohydrates and fat so you're
getting the 28 grams of protein which is
great you're also getting a nice amount
of sodium here as well it's just eight
percent of the intake but sodium is a
really cool thing to include in post
worker and also pre-workout nutrition
because we do lose sodium when we work
out that's why your salt is sweaty it's
really important for hydration you've
also got creatine here you've got beta
in anhydrous ingredients that I
mentioned in our top pick for
post-workout nutrition and then finally
there are also digestive enzymes in here
called prohydrolase I was internet
provide lace in that as an enzyme blend
that is patented is kind of owned by a
company they actually have done proper
studies on this exact blend of enzymes
that have shown pretty positive results
again as far as like speed of absorption
and effectiveness of absorption as well
so basically this is a protein shake and
a non-stem pre-workout post-workout
supplement kind of mixing together it
doesn't have everything that this
supplement has but nonetheless if you
like the idea of getting protein after
workout as well as some ingredients to
improve your next workout re-cage is a
pretty interesting bet so let's talk
about carbohydrate supplements we talked
about the practically carb-free protein
supplements what if you're trying to get
a whole bunch of carbohydrates pretty
easily and you don't want to be
consuming like a whole ton of sugar for
that you just want to check out X work
motion because not all carbohydrates are
created equal right there are several
kinds of carbohydrates out there and the
idea behind Xbox motion is that it is
it's a kind of a new kind of
carbohydrate it got engineered by a
scientists in Japan it's called cluster
dextrin and long and short of it is that
it digests very quickly and doesn't make
you feel bloated class detection is
really cool because for one it's
delicious because they're not trying to
be really low in carbohydrates and there
are also some other benefits in here as
well there are some electrolytes it's
not crazy high in electrolytes but still
you're getting about like a seven eight
nine percent I recommend an intake of a
few of them like sodium magnesium and
calcium and you've got branched chain
amino acids in here as well three grams
of branched chain amino acids so a lot
of folks will enjoy taking this as a mid
workout as an intro workout supplement
as well post workout this is a really
good way to get a bunch of carbs that
won't make you feel bloated and help to
replete your glycogen stores but because
there's no stimulus in here you can kind
of get any time of day as well so the
best post workout creatine if you know
anything or two about creatine you're
going to be happy with our pick because
it is just straight creatine you don't
really need bells and whistles when it
comes to creatine this is Wolverines
creatine monohydrate the ingredients
list is two words and one item creatine
monohydrates five grams non-gmar oh it's
vegan it's gluten free and there are
just no extra bells and whistles or
flavorings that would enhance the price
and also make it more bulky and just
yeah add unnecessary expense right so
this is our favorite creatine
monohydrate product and it's also worth
noting that it's 88 cents per serving
which is pretty inexpensive for creatine
these days inflation has been hitting
just about everything in the entire
world the last few years the creatine
industry in particular has had a pretty
rough goal of it but anyway long story
shots Wolverine keeping it under a buck
press serving and that far under a buck
per serving it's actually a bit of a
feat so yeah we're a big fan of
silverens creatine for a few reasons so
this is a more interesting one and this
is the post workout greens powder which
is my green superfood powders here right
that's what they're typically called
This is the ag1 product from athletic
greens this is also shockingly
nutritious because a lot of greens
powders actually really don't have many
vitamins and minerals because they're
focusing on other stuff but it's
actually has quite a lot of vitamins and
minerals including well over 100 of the
recommended intake of like vitamin C
vitamin E B12 zinc and more but the real
thing to emphasize here is the
antioxidant content right so this has a
whole ton of Spirulina in it wheat grass
powder chlorella Alfalfa all the basic
Mainstays of greens powders that are
included in these sorts of products
because they're very very dense with
antioxidants but interestingly you've
also got rhodiola rosea and some
adaptogens in this even got some
probiotics and digestive enzymes in
there as well to improve gut health and
Prebiotic fiber as well to help with the
gut health so that sounds a little bit
less to do with the pose workout
nutrition more to do with overall health
but generally uh yeah a feeling for an
antioxidant supplement to health speed
recovery this has plenty of them plus
the adaptogens plus a bunch of other
stuff that's just good for you as well
so yeah ag1 we're big fans of here at
Broadband all right now what if you like
a little extra help sleeping that's
especially true for a lot of folks if
they work out after work like after the
office so focal has night here which is
our favorite post-workout supplement for
better sleep like a lot of effective
sleep aids these days they are employing
cannabidiol CBD so there are 22
milligrams of CBD for every two pill
serving there's a lot of other stuff
here as well like 5-HTP 5htp has
interesting links with production of
serotonin in the brain and also it helps
you to potentially produce your own
melatonin there's also Valerian
ashwagandha and some other adaptogens in
this so pretty cool product is all made
in the USA if you go to the website you
can see that it's been third-party
tested they're like a certificate of
analysis of all the ingredients so you
can feel really confident that you're
getting what you're getting and nothing
else so focal night yeah they really do
a good job of uh including a little
different angles with which they could
potentially help to improve your Sleep
Quality all right now let's talk about
essential amino acids that's where intra
comes in uh we often get asked the best
post workout with EAA essentially amino
acids intra is an intro workout
supplement you can also take post
workouts so intro from transparent Labs
is a really cool product there's a wide
range of amino acids in here not just
the branched chain amino acids
transparent Labs the legit there are
nine essential amino acids in this
product and on top of that there's some
extra ingredients like electrolytes so
that's calcium magnesium sodium and
potassium and also some of the
ingredients commonly found in
pre-workout ingredients not the caffeine
but we've got a taurine which has links
to focus there's beta anhydrous again
this tyrosine also links to focus and
also some estrogen which is like an
astragalus extract that can help to
improve absorption and the cherry on top
is that there are no artificial flavors
or sweeteners in this which is
especially remarkable here because amino
acids on their own they're typically
quite bitter and typically you need a
lot of artificial flavors and Sweetness
in there to make them palatable this one
doesn't have it and it still tastes
pretty darn good this and it's no sugar
either and it's also vegan and
gluten-free now talk about the essential
amino acid supplements but if you are
more interested in branched chain amino
acid supplements which tends to be a bit
less expensive uh Wolverines is our pick
for the best first workout branched
chain amino acid supplement the
engineering of brown skin amino acids is
that you can contact them before or
during or after workout or you know kind
of any time of day again because they
are not stimulants but a lot of folks
like to take them right after your
workout especially if it's going to be a
little while between finishing the
workout and having a nice big proper
meal right they'll take the branched
amino acids partly before muscle
retention but also because it can
potentially help to improve recovery and
reduce muscle soreness there's been some
interesting research there on BCAAs
helping with muscle soreness the next
day this is the lemon lime flavor from
Wolverine this one doesn't have any
artificial flavors either it does have
an artificial sweetener but as I said I
kind of prefer artificial sweeteners in
BCAA supplements because usually you
need it transparent Labs does a good job
but uh yeah Wolverines this has like the
normal flavors you'll find in these
sorts of products which means you're
kind of in for intrigued and it makes
for a post-workout drink that it's
actually pretty nice to consume so this
is our favorite BCAA for post workout
the last entry on our list of course is
the biggest post-workout supplement it
is the best post workout for mass
gaining we could have mass gaining here
from transparent Labs it is the biggest
tub because it is the most calories
this one here is 750 calories for every
serving that's two scrubs and the thing
is obviously you can just have like less
of it if you want to have a smaller you
know post workout Shake 750 calories
here and now you're getting 14 grams of
fat 110 grams of carbohydrates and 53
grams of protein so that's like a basic
one to two ratio of protein to carbs
it's very very common in athletes
beginning six rounds of fiber here as
well what's really cool is it's 110
grams of carbohydrates but it's just 12
grams of sugar and there's no added
sugar in here on top of that like the
Whey is grass fed there's also got all
natural ingredients there's no
artificial flavors or sweeteners either
and all the carbohydrates largely come
from organic tapioca and sweet potato
fiber and also oat flour but I really
like the transferring Labs it's largely
you know food ground up and into a
delicious chocolate flavor that tastes
good because they're not trying to keep
it low carb so that does a four hour
Guide to the best post workout
supplements before you go out and buy
yourself a post-workout stuff man there
are a few things to remember the main
thing is that when it comes to
performance and your recovery the most
important things to note your overall
calories your overall macronutrients
split like if you're getting enough
protein and carbs and fat and your sleep
and your workouts themselves right
supplements are just that they're
supplements and they can help to sort of
like fill in any gaps that can appear in
your diet so whether it's for
micronutrients as in the case of like
say athletic greens or whether it's for
macronutrients like in the case of a
mascara of a protein powder or a
carbohydrate supplement there's a bunch
of different ways to approach nutrition
and your lifestyle and your athletic
goals and in this array of supplements
here we think that whatever you're
struggling with and whatever you want a
little bit of extra help with there's
something here that's going to be right
for you so thanks for watching this
video again if you want to see this
whole article in written form this whole
video in written form we have an article
for it on Google if you just write a bar
band best post-workout supplements this
article will come right up and then you
can get all the information there to
read at your own pace and make an
informed choice so that's it for our
video thanks for watching and I will see
you next time foreign